another equation that we will very often
use is amal's law which we need to use
when we are about to speed up only part
of the program only some instructions
and so on so basically when we have a
speed up but it doesn't apply to the
entire program and we want to know what
is the overall speed up on the entire
program so the overall speed up can be
computed as 1 over 1 minus the fraction
of the program we didn't enhance so for
example if we sped up 40% of the program
then this would be
60% plus the fraction of the program we
did enhance in this case the 40% divided
by the speed up we achieve on that
enhancement how did we get there so the
speed up in this case is the Improvement
in performance which is one over the new
execution time relative to the old so
this is the part that we didn't improve
just stays there the part that we did
improve is shorter by the amount of
improvement on that part it's very very
very important to understand that the
fraction enhanced here is a percentage
of the original execution time that is
affected by our
enhancement okay so it needs to be that
40% of the time spent on the program is
affected by your speed up not for
example 40% of the instructions in the
program or something else other than the
time